Finding Aid for Makepeace Uho Tsao ONCE Festival collection, 1962-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Makepeace Uho Tsao ONCE Festival collection 1962-1982 1963-1966
Tsao, Makepeace Uho, collector
0.3 linear feet (in 2 oversize folders)
2011044 UAm; UAl
Posters, programs, and flyers advertising events of the ONCE Festival, collected by Makepeace Uho Tsao.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This collection was donated by Karen Tsao (donor no. 10495 ) in February 2011.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Makepeace Uho Tsao received Ph.D. in Pharmacological Chemistry from the University of Michigan in 1944 and worked at the University of Michigan Pediatric Research Lab and served as assistant and associate professor of Biochemistry in the School of Medicine, as well as clinically at the University hospital. He later taught at the University of California at Davis. While teaching at the University of Michigan in the early 1960s, Tsao became associated with the avant-garde arts group ONCE. The ONCE Group was founded by Ann Arbor artists Robert Ashley, George Cacioppo, Gordon Mumma, Roger Reynolds, and Donald Scavarda. It included musicians, visual artists, architects, and film-makers. The group created the ONCE Festival of music that became an arena for avant-garde and experimental acoustic and electronic music performances in the late 1950s-early 1960s.
The collection consists of two folders of color and black and white posters, flyers, advertisements, programs, mailing cards, etc., announcing events of the ONCE Festival performances and activities. The items are arranged in chronological order, except for two extra-large items separately located in a second folder.
Subjects:
ONCE Festival.; Avant-garde (Music); Music festivals--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre Terms:
Posters.
- Posters, programs, and flyers
  - New Music Pianos Series, 1962/1963., Poster, black & white, 12.3 x 21.6 (Folder 1)
  - ONCE, February 9-17, 1963., Poster, black & white, 16.5 x 21.8 (Folder 1)
  - ONCE, February 9-17, 1963., Program, black & white, 8.3 x 21.8 (Folder 1)
  - Films: the First Ann Arbor Film Festival, May 23-26, 1963., Poster and program, black & white, 16 x 9.5 (Folder 1)
  - ONCE, February 25-March 1, 1964., 2 items; Poster and program, mauve on white, 16.1 x 10.1 (Folder 1)
  - ONCE, February 11-14, 1965., Deck of 18 cards in manila envelope, color, 2.5 x 3.5 cards in 3 x 4.3 envelope; 2 sets (Folder 1)
  - ONCE 1965. February 11-14, 1965., Poster, blue type on brown paper, 11 x 17 (Folder 1)
  - ONCE Again, 1965. September 17-19, 1965., Poster, black & white, 20 x 14 (Folder 1)
  - ONCE-OFF, Kitty Hawks performance, April 9, 1965., Mailer, black & white, 4 x 9 (Folder 1)
  - ONCE-OFF. Kitty Hawks performance, April 9, 1965., Airplane sheet, black & white, 8.3 x 10.5 (Folder 1)
  - ONCE-OFF. Kitty Hawks performance, April 9, 1965., Folded airplane, black & white, 8.3 x 10.5 (Folder 1)
  - First Festival of Live-Electronic Music, 1967. UC Davis, December 4-6, 1967., Flyer with program, black on blue, 11 x 15 (Folder 1)
  - Sonic Art Union. 1971(?) or 1972(?). Robert Ashley, David Behrman, Alvin Lucier, Gordon Mumma., Promotion packet containing loose-leaf booklet, black & white, 7 x 10.2 (Folder 1)
  - M.U.S.I.C.: Marvelous Unlimited Sounds in Concert. San Francisco, December 1-5, 1982., Program, black on orange, 14 x 8.5 (Folder 1)
  - Collages. Red Door Gallery, Detroit, Mich., undated., Poster, black & white, 12.3 x 9.3 (Folder 1)
  - Five sporting events @ The Red Door Gallery. Detroit, Mich., undated., Advertising, black & white, 8 x 15 (Folder 1)
  - ONCE more June 18... Undated., Flyer, black & white, 12.3 x 8.5 (Folder 1)
  - Space Theatre: Manifestations in light and sound. Undated., Poster, color, 3.5 x 17.5 (Folder 1)
  - Make piece. Image used for poster and program, ONCE February 25-March 1, 1964., Sepiaprint, 54 x 36 (Folder 2)
  - Spag[h]etti & Reos. ONCE Febuary 11-14, 1965., Sepiaprint, 39 x 36 (Folder 2)